<tool id="interactive_tool_phyloseq" tool_type="interactive" name="Phyloseq" version="1.0.0" profile="23.1">
    <description>Explore microbiome profiles</description>
    <requirements>
        <container type="docker">quay.io/paulzierep/shinyphyloseq:0.1</container>
    </requirements>
    <entry_points>
        <entry_point name="Phyloseq" requires_domain="True">
            <!-- This port is exposed by the docker container -->
            <port>3838</port>
        </entry_point>
    </entry_points>
    <command><![CDATA[
    mkdir -p ./shiny_input ./shiny_output &&

    export SHINY_INPUT_DIR=\$PWD/shiny_input &&
    export SHINY_OUTPUT_DIR=\$PWD/shiny_output &&

    ln -sf '$input' \$SHINY_INPUT_DIR &&

    Rscript /app_setup.R

    ]]>
    </command>
    <inputs>
        <param name="input" type="data" format="phyloseq" label="Phyloseq R object"
            help="A phyloseq object stored as RDS file. If only a RData object is available the phyloseq object needs to be extracted first."/>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <collection name="output_collection" type="list" label="RData collection">
            <discover_datasets pattern="__designation_and_ext__" directory="./shiny_output" visible="false"/>
        </collection>
    </outputs>
    <tests>
        <test expect_num_outputs="1"/>
    </tests>
    <help><![CDATA[

**Overview**

The analysis of microbial communities brings many challenges: the integration of many different types of data with methods from ecology, genetics, phylogenetics,
network analysis, visualization and testing. The data itself may originate from widely different sources, such as the microbiomes of humans, soils, surface and ocean waters,
wastewater treatment plants, industrial facilities, and so on; and as a result, these varied sample types may have very different forms and scales of related data that
is extremely dependent upon the experiment and its question(s). The phyloseq package is a tool to import, store, analyze, and graphically display complex
phylogenetic sequencing data that has already been clustered into Operational Taxonomic Units (OTUs), especially when there is associated sample data, phylogenetic
tree, and/or taxonomic assignment of the OTUs.

Full documentation: https://joey711.github.io/phyloseq/

**Shiny App**       

This IT uses https://github.com/joey711/shiny-phyloseq as the basis app but added some features that allow loading phyloseq objects dynamically from the Galaxy Input.
The shiny app allows to interactively visualize and filer amplicon data:

* Filter
* Alpha Diversity
* Network plots
* d3Network plots
* Ordination plots
* Heatmaps
* Tree plots
* Scatter pots
* Bar charts

Unfortunately, the following features of the app are currently defunct: provenance. 
        
]]></help>
    <citations>
        <citation type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0061217</citation>
    </citations>
</tool>
